<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Web | Spenser Jones]]></title>
  <link href="http://spenserj.com/blog/categories/web/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://spenserj.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-26T23:06:21-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://spenserj.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Spenser Jones]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prevent Server Version Leaks in MediaWiki's Special:Version]]></title>
    <link href="http://spenserj.com/blog/2013/07/19/prevent-server-version-leaks-in-mediawikis-special-version/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-19T16:34:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://spenserj.com/blog/2013/07/19/prevent-server-version-leaks-in-mediawikis-special-version</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Setting up a knowledge base or wiki is a great way of keeping people (coworkers, clients, strangers, and anyone else you can think of) informed about certain topics, and MediaWiki is one of the most popular choices for this. It powers Wikipedia, the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia">worlds largest general reference work</a>, and thousands of other wikis on a variety of subjects.</p>

<p>While obscuring version information should never be your only form of security, it makes life slightly harder for anyone looking to vandalize or penetrate your webserver. By default, MediaWiki will tell anyone who will listen what software you&rsquo;re running (<a href="https://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/Special:Version">example</a>), and there is no obvious way of disabling this. The solution? Let&rsquo;s dig into the code behind this page, and cut it off at the source.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Open up <code>includes/specials/SpecialVersion.php</code>, and locate the <code>execute</code> function (somewhere around line 50). You&rsquo;ll find a variable called <code>$text</code> that will contain all of the information to be displayed, and one of the functions it calls is <code>softwareInformation()</code>. If you comment out the entire line and save the file, you&rsquo;ll plug MediaWiki&rsquo;s version leak.</p>

<p>``` php includes/specials/SpecialVersion.php &ndash; SpecialVersion->execute
public function execute( $par ) {
  global $wgSpecialVersionShowHooks;
  $this->setHeaders();
  $this->outputHeader();
  $out = $this->getOutput();
  $out->allowClickjacking();</p>

<p>  $text =</p>

<pre><code>$this-&gt;getMediaWikiCredits() .
// Commented out to stop the version leak
// $this-&gt;softwareInformation() .
$this-&gt;getEntryPointInfo() .
$this-&gt;getExtensionCredits();
</code></pre>

<p>```</p>

<h2>Kill it with fire</h2>

<p>If removing your software version doesn&rsquo;t leave you feeling satisfied, you can remove the page entirely by commenting out a line in <code>includes/SpecialPageFactory.php</code>. I&rsquo;m not a fan of this extreme step, as it removes recognition for the developers, licensing information, and a list of the extensions you&rsquo;re using, none of which are a security risk.</p>

<p>``` php includes/SpecialPageFactory.php</p>

<pre><code>// Wiki data and tools
'Statistics'                =&gt; 'SpecialStatistics',
'Allmessages'               =&gt; 'SpecialAllmessages',
// Commented out to remove the Special:Version page entirely
// 'Version'                   =&gt; 'SpecialVersion',
'Lockdb'                    =&gt; 'SpecialLockdb',
'Unlockdb'                  =&gt; 'SpecialUnlockdb',
</code></pre>

<p>```</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Upgrading a Moodle 1.9 Block to 2.0]]></title>
    <link href="http://spenserj.com/blog/2011/04/14/upgrading-a-moodle-1-dot-9-block-to-2-dot-0/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-14T12:55:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://spenserj.com/blog/2011/04/14/upgrading-a-moodle-1-dot-9-block-to-2-dot-0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently went through the process of upgrading a Moodle 1.9 block for Panopto, to support Moodle 2.0, which came out in January. As Moodle 2.0 is a huge rewrite, and is still fairly fresh, there is very little documentation on what changes need to be made, or even what functions are deprecated and need replacing. In order to upgrade the plugin at Ambrose University College, I read through multiple core classes, and compared functions in 1.9 to 2.0. In order to make things easier for myself in the future, and for anyone else upgrading a block, I have documented my changes.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Language strings must be listed in <code>blockname/lang/en/block_blockname.php</code>, and one of the strings must be the plugin name:</p>

<p><code>php blockname/lang/en/block_blockname.php
&lt;?php
$string['pluginname'] = 'Epic Block';
$string['name_of_string'] = 'English version of string';
</code></p>

<p>The version has been moved from <code>blockname/blocks_blockname.php</code> to <code>blockname/version.php</code>. The format of the version remains the same (yyyymmdd00, where 00 can increment if you release multiple patches on a single day)</p>

<p><code>php blockname/version.php
&lt;?php
$plugin-&gt;version = 2011040800;
</code></p>

<p>The function for checking if the current user is a teacher who can edit the current course has changed, as have a few others, so use this as a base, and read through the core classes for the correct values.</p>

<p><code>php
if(isteacheredit($COURSE-&gt;id)) {
</code></p>

<p>has now become</p>

<p><code>php
$context = get_context_instance(CONTEXT_COURSE, $COURSE-&gt;id);
if(has_capability('moodle/course:update', $context)) {
</code></p>

<p>Stylesheets are now in <code>style.css</code>, instead of <code>style.php</code>.</p>

<p>Configuration files have also changed, as <code>config_instance.html</code> has been replaced with <code>edit_form.php</code> (below), and <code>config_global.html</code> has been replaced with <code>settings.php</code> (below <code>edit_form.php</code>).</p>

<p>``` php edit_form.php
&lt;?php
require_once(&ldquo;lib/panopto_data.php&rdquo;);</p>

<p>class block_panopto_edit_form extends block_edit_form {
  protected function specific_definition($mform) {</p>

<pre><code>global $COURSE, $CFG;

// Construct the Panopto data proxy object
$panopto_data = new panopto_data($COURSE-&gt;id);

if(!empty($panopto_data-&gt;servername) &amp;&amp; !empty($panopto_data-&gt;instancename) &amp;&amp; !empty($panopto_data-&gt;applicationkey))
{
  $mform-&gt;addElement('header', 'configheader', 'Select the Panopto CourseCast course to display in this block.');

  $params-&gt;course_ids = $COURSE-&gt;id;
  $params-&gt;return_url = urlencode($_SERVER['REQUEST_URI']);
  $query_string = http_build_query($params);
  $provision_url = "$CFG-&gt;wwwroot/blocks/panopto/provision_course.php?" . $query_string;
  $course_list = $panopto_data-&gt;get_course_options($provision_url);
  $mform-&gt;addElement('selectgroups', 'config_course', 'Course', $course_list['courses']);
  $mform-&gt;setDefault('config_course', $course_list['selected']);
} else {
  $mform-&gt;addElement('static', 'error', '', 'Cannot configure block instance: Global configuration incomplete. Please contact your system administrator.');
}
</code></pre>

<p>  }
}
```</p>

<p>``` php settings.php
&lt;?php</p>

<p>defined(&lsquo;MOODLE_INTERNAL&rsquo;) || die;</p>

<p>if ($ADMIN->fulltree) {</p>

<pre><code>$settings-&gt;add(new admin_setting_configtext('block_panopto_instance_name', 'Moodle Instance Name',
                   'This value is prefixed before usernames and course-names in Panopto.', 'moodle', PARAM_TEXT));

$settings-&gt;add(new admin_setting_configtext('block_panopto_server_name', 'Panopto Server Hostname', '', '', PARAM_TEXT));

$settings-&gt;add(new admin_setting_configtext('block_panopto_application_key', 'Application Key', '', '', PARAM_TEXT));

$link ='&lt;a href="'.$CFG-&gt;wwwroot.'/blocks/panopto/provision_course.php"&gt;Add Moodle courses to Panopto CourseCast&lt;/a&gt;';
$settings-&gt;add(new admin_setting_heading('block_panopto_add_courses', '', $link));
</code></pre>

<p>}
```</p>

<p>There are many more changes that occurred, and this post is only the tip of the iceberg, so post a comment if you can&rsquo;t find the replacement for a deprecated function, and I&rsquo;ll do my best to help you out. If you want to see a legitimate commit for the changes that I made to upgrade a 1.9 block to a working 2.0 block, take a look at <a href="https://github.com/SpenserJ/Moodle2-Panopto/commit/ca893577b7d34adbeca6e95f5fe2f54194d488a3">this commit</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fixing the Blackbaud NetCommunity Login Form]]></title>
    <link href="http://spenserj.com/blog/2011/04/14/fixing-the-blackbaud-netcommunity-login-form/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-14T12:52:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://spenserj.com/blog/2011/04/14/fixing-the-blackbaud-netcommunity-login-form</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Blackbaud NetCommunity 6.15 has a bug in the login form, where tabbing onto the &ldquo;Remember Me&rdquo; field and pressing enter (normal functionality to submit a form) will take you back to the login form, with your username filled in, but no password or error. This is due to the fact that javascript is being (poorly) added directly to the HTML tags, instead of writing a simple, unobtrusive javascript function, that targets all fields on the form.</p>

<p>To remedy this, add a JS file to any layout that may contain a login field, and add this code:</p>

<p>``` javascript
$(function() {
  if (($loginForm = $(&lsquo;.LoginFormTable&rsquo;)).length &gt; 0) {</p>

<pre><code>$('input[type!=submit]', $loginForm).keypress(function(e) {
  if ((e.which &amp;amp;&amp;amp; e.which == 13) || (e.keyCode &amp;amp;&amp;amp; event.ke == 13)) {
    $('input[type=submit]', $loginForm).click();
    return false;
  } else { return true; }
});
</code></pre>

<p>  }
});
```</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Adding iFrames to Blackbaud NetCommunity <= 6.15.70]]></title>
    <link href="http://spenserj.com/blog/2011/03/25/adding-iframes-to-blackbaud-netcommunity/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-25T12:47:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://spenserj.com/blog/2011/03/25/adding-iframes-to-blackbaud-netcommunity</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Version 6.15 of Blackbaud NetCommunity consisted of many large changes to how BBNC works, one of which was the editor. In this update, Blackbaud moved from BBCuteEditor to TinyMCE (a great decision IMO, as TinyMCE is one of the most popular WYSIWYG editors). Sadly, patch 70 and below do not support iFrames, even if you have the iFrame set as a &ldquo;Safe HTML Tag&rdquo; in the settings. Blackbaud is working on a patch for this (patch 71 to be exact), however they do not have an ETA for it yet.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>We have always had maps embedded in our website, to help visitors find us, and we recently decided to also embed a few YouTube videos. Due to the change in 6.15 however, we could no longer do so, and I went on a hunt to find the key to the iFrame kingdom. After using the find-in-file feature of Windows, and coming up short on anything, I wrote a quick little script to rewrite the editor initialization code, remove existing editors, and reinitialize them, with the iframe allowed. It wasn&rsquo;t the most elegant solution, however it worked for the interm, as I waited for Blackbaud to release P71. While implementing it however, I stumbled across the original initialization code, and instantly threw what I had written out.</p>

<p>Since it took a while for me to find this, I figure it may come in handy for anyone else that needs to add iFrames to TinyMCE in Blackbaud NetCommunity, or for anyone wanting to tweak the editor in the future.</p>

<p>The file that you&rsquo;ll want to edit is <code>{NetCommunity}/admin/HTMLEditorControl2.ascx</code>. For adding iFrames to the valid elements, I changed:</p>

<p><code>plain
&lt;appfx:HtmlEditorSetting Name="extended_valid_elements" Value="'style[dir&amp;lt;ltr?rtl|lang|media|title|type]
</code></p>

<p>to:</p>

<p><code>plain
&lt;appfx:HtmlEditorSetting Name="extended_valid_elements" Value="'iframe[src|width|height|name|align],style[dir&amp;lt;ltr?rtl|lang|media|title|type]
</code></p>

<p>Save the file, and refresh the editor, and you should now be able to insert iFrames into your page. Through this file, you can also change the theme that is used, disable certain toolbar buttons, and adjust anything else that is in the <a href="http://tinymce.moxiecode.com/wiki.php/Configuration">TinyMCE Configuration</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Creating a Blackbaud NetCommunity Custom Part]]></title>
    <link href="http://spenserj.com/blog/2011/02/23/creating-a-blackbaud-netcommunity-custom-part/"/>
    <updated>2011-02-23T18:32:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://spenserj.com/blog/2011/02/23/creating-a-blackbaud-netcommunity-custom-part</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve recently been given the task of creating some custom plugins for NetCommunity, so we can do things like unify the design of our Faculty Biography pages at Ambrose. I have prior experience with C#, so I figured it would be a fairly simple process, once I figured out how their API works, however there is minimal documentation, and all of the tutorials online are either outdated or incomplete.</p>

<p>As such, I am going to write up a concise walkthrough for creating a NetCommunity plugin (for 6.15) using C#, from scratch, up until you have a functional part.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Begin by creating a new &ldquo;ASP.NET Empty Web Application&rdquo; project in Microsoft Visual Web Developer (<a href="http://cl.ly/4nce">http://cl.ly/4nce</a>). Right click on References, in the Solution Explorer, and choose Add Reference. Under the Browse tab, navigate to the Bin folder of your NetCommunity installation, and choose <code>BBNCExtensions.dll</code> (<a href="http://cl.ly/4nOt">http://cl.ly/4nOt</a>). Finally, go into the Project menu, and click <code>{ProjectName} properties</code>, and change Target framework to <code>.NET Framework 3.5</code> (under the application tab). You&rsquo;re now ready to start coding some basic functionality into your application.</p>

<p>Right click on your project in the Solution Explorer (should be the bold title at the very top), and choose <code>Add-&gt;New Item</code>. You will want to create two new <code>Web User Controls</code> named <code>Display.ascx</code> and <code>Editor.ascx</code> (<a href="http://cl.ly/4n69">http://cl.ly/4n69</a>). In Display.ascx.cs and Editor.ascx.cs, add the following &ldquo;using&rdquo; statements:</p>

<p><code>c# Display.ascx.cs and Editor.ascx.cs
using BBNCExtensions;
using BBNCExtensions.Parts;
</code></p>

<p>Then, in <code>Display.ascx.cs</code>, change <code>System.WebUI.UserControl</code> (the class to inherit from) to <code>BBNCExtensions.Parts.CustomPartDisplayBase</code>. In <code>Editor.ascx.cs</code>, you&rsquo;ll want to change <code>System.WebUI.UserControl</code> to <code>BBNCExtensions.Parts.CustomPartEditorBase</code>. You&rsquo;ll also want to add two functions, as follow:</p>

<p>``` c# Display.ascx.cs
public override void OnLoadContent() {</p>

<p>}</p>

<p>public override bool OnSaveContent(bool bDialogIsClosing){</p>

<pre><code>return true;
</code></pre>

<p>}
```</p>

<p>Your plugin is now finished, and it is time to build it, and set it up in NetCommunity. Click build, and copy <code>bin/{ProjectName}.dll</code> to <code>{NetCommunityInstall}/Bin</code>, and copy <code>Display.ascx</code> and <code>Editor.ascx</code> (from the project root) to <code>{NetCommunityInstall}/Custom/{ProjectName}/</code>. Then open up the Custom Part settings page in NetCommunity, click <code>New custom part</code>, and give your part a name. For Display/Edit Control Source, enter <code>~\Custom\{ProjectName}\{Display|Editor}.ascx</code> (depending on which field you&rsquo;re changing), and leave <code>Supports Personalization for</code> set to <code>Not Supported</code>.</p>

<p>Save the custom part, and try creating a part, and you should see a blank editor page, and a blank display page (after you save it). Your NetCommunity plugin is now built, so give yourself a pat on the back, take a quick break, and then we&rsquo;ll add some basic functionality.</p>

<p>Every change you make will require that you update either the DLL, the ascx files, or both (depending on what you change), so lets automate that with some build events. Click the Project Menu, and then <code>{ProjectName} Properties</code>. Open the Build Events tab, and edit the Post-build event so that it reads (with obvious path adjustments):</p>

<p><code>plain
copy "$(ProjectDir)*.ascx"  "c:\Program Files\Blackbaud\NetCommunity\Custom\$(ProjectName)"
copy "$(TargetDir)$(ProjectName).dll" "c:\Program Files\Blackbaud\NetCommunity\Bin"
</code></p>

<p>Click build, and you should see it automatically copy the three files into their appropriate directories.</p>

<p>Now to bring the plugin to life, and add some actual functionality. Right click on your project in the Solution Explorer, and choose <code>Add-&gt;Class</code>. Name it something appropriate, as this class will hold the settings for this part. Inside of the class declaration, add a public variable for every property of the part (e.g. public string name = &ldquo;&rdquo;;).</p>

<p>Open <code>Editor.ascx</code> in design mode, and add a text field (you can add labels and formatting whenever you please) for each property that you want to make editable, and set the ID to match the property name. I chose to prefix each with &ldquo;field&rdquo; to make it easier to find, which resulted in things like &ldquo;fieldEducation&rdquo; as an ID, but as long as you can keep track of each property, you can name it any proper variable name.</p>

<p>Then, go back to <code>Editor.ascx.cs</code>, and in your <code>OnSaveContent</code> function, add the following (adjusting as necessary). I&rsquo;m going to use property_class, but replace that with whatever you named the class you created above (containing your property declarations):</p>

<p><code>c# Editor.ascx.cs - OnSaveContent
// Lets create an empty property_class variable, to save our data
property_class save_data = new property_class();
// For each property that you have, add a line similar to this
save_data.education = fieldEducation.Text;
// Now lets save all of those properties to the part
base.Content.SaveContent(save_data);
// Finally, let the browser know that everything worked, and let the window close
// When you add validation, return false if you find an error
return true;
</code></p>

<p>While still in <code>Editor.ascx.cs</code>, add the following to <code>OnLoadContent</code>, again modifying it as needed:</p>

<p>``` c# Editor.ascx.cs &ndash; OnLoadContent
// Check if we&rsquo;re not updating the data (e.g. we just opened the editor)
if (Request.RequestType != &ldquo;POST&rdquo;)
{</p>

<pre><code>// Load the content from our part, as property_class
property_class get_data = base.Content.GetContent(typeof(property_class)) as property_class;
// If get_data is null, this is a brand new part. If it isn't null, lets set our fields to the data
if (get_data != null)
{
    // Add a line like this for every property in property_class
    fieldEducation.Text = get_data.education;
}
</code></pre>

<p>}
```</p>

<p>If you build the part, and try it in NetCommunity at this point, you&rsquo;ll find that you can create and edit the part, and it will retain your changes, however it doesn&rsquo;t display your changes anywhere. To add that in, open up <code>Display.ascx</code> in design mode, and add Literal tags to your code, again, setting the ID to something logical. Then open up <code>Display.ascx.cs</code>, and add the following to your <code>Page_Load</code> function, as usual, editing it where needed:</p>

<p>``` c# Display.ascx &ndash; Page_Load
// Load the content from our part, as property_class
property_class get_data = base.Content.GetContent(typeof(property_class)) as property_class;
// Has this part been saved before?
if (get_data != null)
{</p>

<pre><code>// Add a line like this for every property in property_class
fieldEducation.Text = get_data.education;
</code></pre>

<p>}
```</p>

<p>If you save and build your part again, you&rsquo;ll see that your properties are now being displayed as well. Congratulations on successfully building your first Blackbaud NetCommunity Custom Part.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
