<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Spenser Jones]]></title>
  <link href="http://SpenserJ.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://SpenserJ.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-07-12T11:39:19-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://SpenserJ.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Spenser Jones]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Setting up NSD3 for DNS]]></title>
    <link href="http://SpenserJ.github.io/blog/2013/07/12/setting-up-nsd3-for-dns/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-12T11:31:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://SpenserJ.github.io/blog/2013/07/12/setting-up-nsd3-for-dns</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Testing, 1 2 3. This is a test.]]></title>
    <link href="http://SpenserJ.github.io/blog/2013/07/12/testing-1-2-3-this-is-a-test/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-12T10:54:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://SpenserJ.github.io/blog/2013/07/12/testing-1-2-3-this-is-a-test</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve decided to give <a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</a> a chance, and so far I&rsquo;m enjoying it far more than <a href="https://drupal.org/">Drupal</a>. While a content management framework is great, I&rsquo;ve always found that there is far too much bloat for it to be used as a blogging platform. On top of that, <a href="http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/">Markdown</a> is a fantastic language, and being able to easily write beautiful code through it is extremely enticing.</p>

<p>Only time will tell if this results in me posting more frequently, but I&rsquo;m optimistic.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building the Science Lab]]></title>
    <link href="http://SpenserJ.github.io/blog/2013/05/14/building-the-science-lab/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-14T19:53:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://SpenserJ.github.io/blog/2013/05/14/building-the-science-lab</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There have been a significant number of bugs with the <a href="http://pecl.php.net/package/APC">Alternative PHP Cache (APC)</a> over the past year, causing me to pass over PHP updates for fear of segfaults, however that has finally come to an end. APC is still just as buggy, but <a href="https://wiki.php.net/rfc/optimizerplus">PHP 5.5</a> will be bringing <a href="http://pecl.php.net/package/ZendOpcache">Zend OPCache</a> to the core, so I&rsquo;ve decided to transition early and configure the PECL package. As Zend OPCache does not come with a User Cache, I decided to set up Memcache on the <a href="https://ambrose.edu/">Ambrose University College</a> Drupal website, and was seeing benchmarks of around 65 requests per second (up from 30-35 req/sec with APC only).</p>

<p>As <a href="https://github.com/krakjoe/apcu">APCu</a> (userland caching) continues to branch from the crusty old APC branch, and the old APC Opcaching code is remove, I&rsquo;ll be running a few tests to see whether APCu can bring more to the table than Memcache can, as I have no need for the distributed functionality that Memcache provides.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spring Cleaning]]></title>
    <link href="http://SpenserJ.github.io/blog/2013/05/14/spring-cleaning/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-14T13:39:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://SpenserJ.github.io/blog/2013/05/14/spring-cleaning</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve decided to wipe out a few years worth of hastily written blog posts and start fresh. Fitting, given that I&rsquo;m also switching to <a href="http://spenserj.com">SpenserJ.com</a> as my domain name, after waiting for it to expire for the better part of two years. My vision is for this site to be a landing zone for the various ideas and tweaks that come to me every week.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
