<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Ambrose | Spenser Jones]]></title>
  <link href="http://spenserj.com/blog/categories/ambrose/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://spenserj.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-26T22:58:10-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://spenserj.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Spenser Jones]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Locking down Blackbaud NetCommunity content authoring]]></title>
    <link href="http://spenserj.com/blog/2010/12/20/locking-down-blackbaud-netcommunity-content-authoring/"/>
    <updated>2010-12-20T18:21:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://spenserj.com/blog/2010/12/20/locking-down-blackbaud-netcommunity-content-authoring</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>At Ambrose University College, we run Blackbaud NetCommunity as our CMS, and I&rsquo;ve encountered a few issues with permissions for content authors, and how the editor itself works. Over the past few weeks, in an attempt to improve the experience of both our visitors, and our content authors, I have added a few lines to our website&rsquo;s javascript file (hosted in a document part).</p>

<p>One issue we have run into is that Internet Explorer does not play nice with our CSS3 box shadows (using CSS3Pie), and will save the progressive enhancements that are loaded specifically for IE, as part of the page and/or part, for all browsers. This results in pages that have been edited using IE, showing two box shadows in CSS3 compliant browsers, and only one in IE. Since IE is to blame (and has issues with other parts of the editor), I decided to kill off support for using IE when in administration mode.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>While I was working on my IE-proofing, one of our content authors accidentally clicked the &ldquo;Template Designer&rdquo; button, which resulted in her inserting a part on every page on the website. This is not the first time we have encountered this issue, and last time it happened, it took about two hours to fix, as changes were also made to the HTML of the template. Two lines of javascript later, and the Stylesheet editor and Template Designer buttons no longer appear. If I need to make changes, I can always go through the page finder, but changes are so infrequent that having a front-and-center button is just asking for trouble.</p>

<p>Incase you would like to implement similar &ldquo;fixes&rdquo; on your NetCommunity website, I have the code for 6.10 posted below :)</p>

<p>``` javascript NetCommunity 6.10
$(function() {
  var $adminMenu = $(&lsquo;#bbAdminMenuDiv&rsquo;, top.document);
  var ieDisabledMessage = &lsquo;In order to edit the Ambrose website, please use Firefox. IE support has been disabled due to compatibility issues.&rsquo;;
  if ($.browser.msie &amp;&amp; $adminMenu.length > 0) {</p>

<pre><code>$('div, table, a', $adminMenu).remove();
$adminMenu.append(ieDisabledMessage);
</code></pre>

<p>  }</p>

<p>  if (top.document.location.href.indexOf(&lsquo;/AdminPage.aspx&rsquo;) > -1) {</p>

<pre><code>$('#pagecntnt_AdminToolbar_btn2, #pagecntnt_AdminToolbar_btn3', top.document).remove();
if ($.browser.msie) { $('#pagecntnt_divContentPane', top.document).html(ieDisabledMessage); }
</code></pre>

<p>  }
});
```</p>

<p><em>As of December 22nd, we have upgraded to 6.15, and the administration menu and screens have changed. As such, I have rewritten the code, and it is also posted below</em></p>

<p>``` javascript NetCommunity 6.15
$(function() {
  var $adminMenu = $(&lsquo;#ctl05_bbBetaAdminMenuDiv&rsquo;, top.document);
  var ieDisabledMessage = &lsquo;In order to edit the Ambrose website, please use Firefox. IE support has been disabled due to compatibility issues.&rsquo;;
  if ($.browser.msie &amp;&amp; $adminMenu.length > 0) {</p>

<pre><code>$('ul.bb_mainMenu li:gt(0), .bb_subMenu', $adminMenu).remove();
$('li:first', $adminMenu).html('&lt;h2 style="padding: 0px 12px;"&gt;' + ieDisabledMessage + '&lt;/h2&gt;');
</code></pre>

<p>  }</p>

<p>  if (top.document.location.href.indexOf(&lsquo;ambrose.edu/cms/&rsquo;) > -1) {</p>

<pre><code>$('#pagecntnt_AdminToolbar_btn1lnk, #pagecntnt_AdminToolbar_btn2lnk', top.document).remove();
if ($.browser.msie) { $('#divPage', top.document).css('color','#fff').html(ieDisabledMessage); }
</code></pre>

<p>  }
});
```</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS3 and Pictos]]></title>
    <link href="http://spenserj.com/blog/2010/12/17/css3-and-pictos/"/>
    <updated>2010-12-17T17:24:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://spenserj.com/blog/2010/12/17/css3-and-pictos</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Over the past six months, I&rsquo;ve been charged with redeveloping the <a href="https://www2.ambrose.edu/">Ambrose University College</a> website, using BlackBaud NetCommunity. I worked together with the creative department (mainly focused on print media) for a new design (old one is <del><a href="https://www2.ambrose.edu/">here</a></del> offline), and with many other departments for training in content management and functionality. I&rsquo;ve learned quite a bit through the process, and grown immensely in my skills (primarily CSS and C#.Net). This post, however, is not so much about the experience I went through, as it is with the advancements I&rsquo;ve made when it comes to CSS3 replacing images, and support for it in all major browsers.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>The initial design was thrown together over a few months, as I worked on getting content uploaded, and functionality working. It was not until two weeks ago that I was able to sit back and actually focus on making the website look good, instead of making it functional. Although I am  not a fan of certain aspects of the design, I have focused on improving what I could in it, and providing support for all browsers, including the bane of every designer/developer&hellip; Internet Explorer. During the &ldquo;throw it together to make people happy&rdquo; phase, I used plenty of images for buttons, and the designers rounded corners in all of the header images that we uploaded, however that increases their workload, and makes it harder to tweak buttons in the future (which we end up doing more than I&rsquo;d like to admit). It quickly became apparent that the website would become a time-sink for those that manage it, and a resource-hog for those that view it, if drastic measures were not taken. Which brings me to two weeks ago&hellip;</p>

<p>We have always used box-shadows on the website, as I was not willing to go through the pain of transparent PNGs in IE, however we have buttons below the <a href="https://www2.ambrose.edu/Page.aspx?pid=492">menu</a>, that were image based, and I was told that we were to add more buttons to a <a href="https://www2.ambrose.edu/Page.aspx?pid=475">few</a> <a href="https://www2.ambrose.edu/Page.aspx?pid=389">other</a> <a href="https://www2.ambrose.edu/Page.aspx?pid=548">pages</a>. Since content was 99% online, I took a look at how we could improve the load times for the website, by replacing these buttons with CSS3 buttons.</p>

<p>Just a few days earlier, I had picked up <a href="http://twitter.com/drewwilson">Drew Wilson&rsquo;s</a> <a href="http://pictos.drewwilson.com/">Pictos</a> web-font on sale, and I suggested it to my boss, so we picked up another license and I began to fiddle around with some nice buttons. Through the use of border-radius and -webkit-gradient (and others like -moz), I was able to perfectly replicate what our designer had envisioned, but without using a single image. I quickly replaced five buttons with their CSS3 counterparts, and was working on implementing them on the new pages, when I realized that they did not look very nice in Internet Explorer. In fact, they were a solid colour, and due to a glitch with <a href="http://fetchak.com/ie-css3/">IE-CSS3</a>, had rounded corners appearing 20px+ BELOW the buttons. Needless to say, certain faculty did not appreciate that their primary browser did not handle things properly, and I put some work into fixing things. After dropping <a href="http://css3pie.com/">CSS3Pie</a> into the website, in place of IE-CSS3, things started looking up. Our box-shadows were more realistic, and the corners no longer jumped around like schoolkids overdosing on sugar. With a few more tweaks, (-pie-background to add support for two-point gradients in IE), we were back in action, and IE looked <strong>almost</strong> as good as Chrome and Firefox.</p>

<p>Since we&rsquo;ve implemented these CSS3 buttons, I&rsquo;ve managed to kill off close to 1 MB of images, and we&rsquo;ve implemented mouseovers with minimal effort. When a new page is added to the website, we can also add some sidebar links, with images, without going through the longwinded process of designing new buttons, and finding icons that don&rsquo;t really match with the previous set.</p>

<p><a href="http://pictos.drewwilson.com/">Pictos</a> has already proved itself, and is well worth the money we invested in it, and I would highly suggest checking it out, if you have a few buttons that could do with a fresh new look on your website. And, as new as CSS3 is, with a bit of elbow grease (-webkit, -moz, -o, and -ms take up quite a bit of time to type out for every effect) and some fallback support (CSS3Pie for instance), you can do some gorgeous things while still supporting 99% of users.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
